{"tossups": [{"question": "In this work, a thousand sprites use their wings to \"twitch\" the diamond in acharacter's ear to aid Crispissa. One man sacrifices in fire \"three garters, half a pairof gloves/ and all the trophies of his former loves\". The third canto of this poemdescribes a game of (+) Ombre, after which Clarissa hands the aforementioned man aweapon. The central character, based on Arabella Fermor, is guarded by sylphs. The victim throws snuff in the (*) Baron's nose and demands the return of a stolen object, which then ascends into the heavens, after Umbriel's intervention to Sir Plume in the Cave of Spleen. This poem opens \"What dire offence from am'rous causes springs/ What mighty contests rise from trivial things\". For ten points, name this mock epic about Belinda's haircut by Alexander Pope.", "answer": "The Rape of the Lock", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Rape of the Lock</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Rape of the Lock"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator repeatedly references Anna Novakova's expertise in this field inBohumil Hrabal's Dancing Lessons for the Advanced in Age. A collection with thisword as the first non-the word in its title contains a poem that opens \"Life, friends,is boring. We must not say so.\" That collection centers on \"Huffy Henry\", contains77 (+) songs, and was written by John Berryman. During one of these events, Pahomsees a Bashkir chief and some strangers laughing at him in Leo Tolstoy's (*) How Much Land Does a Man Need? An Edgar Allan Poe poem with this noun in its title sees the narrator standing on a beach as sand drips from his fingers; that poem asks whether \"all that we see or seem\" is but one of these entities within another. For ten points, name these entities which were \"deferred\" in Langston Hughes's Harlem.", "answer": "dreams", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>dreams</u></b>", "acceptable": ["dreams"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this work is said to \"look at [others] as one of the old lions ortigers may have looked at the Christian martyrs\". On her deathbed, one characterasks her mother to tell the protagonist she was never engaged. A (+) boat ride ateleven o'clock is cancelled when one participant's younger brother Randolph falls asleep; the destination of that ride was the (*) Chateau de Chillon. A young lady refuses a ride in Mrs. Walker's carriage after walking around the Pincian Hill with two gentlemen. After being spotted with Mr. Giovanelli at the Colosseum by Winterbourne, the title character develops Roman fever. For ten points, name this novella about the title American socialite written by Henry James.", "answer": "Daisy Miller                                                                                                                                                                                                               ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Daisy Miller</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Daisy Miller"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of this story disagrees with Tom about whether the latter is pissinghis pants. The protagonist of this story realizes that he has no message for Conchawhen a Belgian doctor offers to convey it. One character relays that, in Saragossa, menare laid on the ground and run over to (+) save ammunition. A character nicknamed\"the kid\" unsuccessfully feigns illness. The protagonist of this story lies about where his confederate is (*) hiding. The narrator is being held in a cell with Tom and Juan, all of whom are being put to death by falangistas during the Spanish Civil War, and his lie led to the capture of Roman Gris in a cemetery. For ten points, name this short story in which Pablo Ibbieta is sentenced to death by firing squad written by Jean-Paul Sartre.", "answer": "The Wall (or Le Mur)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Wall</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Wall"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Le Mur"}, {"question": "The protagonist of this novel writes banjo music for Teresa Guiccioli, a characterin his chamber opera. One character in this novel performs in the play Sunset at theGlobe Salon, but the protagonist is attacked with spitballs when he goes to watchit. The protagonist has an affair with (+) Bev Shaw while volunteering at an animalclinic and writes Byron in Italy. He is later irate when Pollux moves in next door, as Pollux and two other men had attacked him and his (*) daughter in her home, setting his head on fire and raping her; that daughter, Lucy, shares her farm with the co-proprietor Petrus. The protagonist loses his job as a communications teacher after an affair with his student, Melanie Isaacs. For ten points, identify this novel about David Lurie written by J. M. Coetzee.", "answer": "Disgrace", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Disgrace</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Disgrace"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this decade, Winterhalter Elementary school in Detroit was firebombed aspart of the Winchell riots. The Iceland Understanding and the Hawaii Understandingwere signed in this decade to prevent war. Metropolitan Life unveiled a programto relocate employees to Danville, Kentucky named after the (+) Homestead Act.The Office of American Absorption sent young boys to inland farms through its Just Folks initiative, which was championed by Rabbi Bengelsdorf. This decade opened with a surprise candidate (*) flying into the Republican National Convention in Philadelphia and winning on an isolationist platform. For ten points, name this decade during which, in Philip Roth's The Plot Against America, Charles Lindbergh was elected president to keep the United States out of World War II.", "answer": "1940s", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>1940s</u></b>", "acceptable": ["1940s"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A character in this location uses a thought experiment to show that the dark spotson the moon are not caused by dense areas. During a conversation in this place, theanalogy of an aimed arrow falling to the ground is given as an answer to \"How fromsweet seed can bitter issue forth\" by (+) Charles Martel. The image of an eagle formsin the sky after spelling out a Latin phrase about loving justice. While in this location, the narrator is temporarily blinded during a questioning on charity, and Cacciaguida predicts that the narrator will be banished from (*) Florence. Before entrance, the narrator bathes in the river Lethe, and he ends his trip in Empyrean, the tenth circle. For ten points, name this location through which Beatrice guided Dante after he visited Purgatorio in The Divine Comedy.", "answer": "Paradiso (or Paradise, prompt on \"heaven\" or equivalents)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Paradiso</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Paradiso"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Paradise, prompt on \"heaven\" or equivalents"}, {"question": "One character in this play claims to have wrestled with Death for three days andnights and uses an excuse of renting furniture from the Devil to avoid lending his sonten dollars. The protagonist of this play repeatedly sings about a dog Blue who \"treeda possum in a hollow log\". This play ends with one character failing to (+) blow hishorn three times. The protagonist's mistress Alberta dies giving birth to Raynell. The protagonist is promoted to (*) driver from his position as garbage man, and he prohibits his son Cory from playing football. For ten points, identify this play in which the former baseball player Troy Maxson builds the title object, written by August Wilson.", "answer": "Fences", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Fences</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Fences"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "While in school, the narrator of this novel helped \"Red Head\" cheat on a spellingtest and was friends with the orator \"Shiny\". The narrator of this novel gives moneyto men who wore linen dusters on their feet because they had gambled away theirshoes at a club in New York City. The narrator (+) hides in the closet of a Pullmancar after dropping out of Atlanta University to get to Jacksonville, where he earns a job as a reader in a cigar factory. The narrator plays (*) ragtime renditions of Mendelsohn's Wedding March while touring Europe with a benefactor. The narrator, whose absentee father was described as \"the best blood of the South\", changes his name and identity after witnessing a lynching. For ten points, name this roman  \u0301a clef by James Weldon Johnson about a black man who passes as white.", "answer": "The Autobiography of an Ex-Colored Man                                                                                                                                                                                                                                              ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Autobiography of an Ex-Colored Man</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Autobiography of an Ex-Colored Man"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A lady in this work cautions that when husbands pay attention to their wivesin public, \"it makes people think that he beats her when they're alone\". Anothercharacter repeatedly asks whether \"this will be the last ball of the season\", gettingdifferent answers each time. The central character of this play finds three questionable(+) payments totalling 1700 pounds when she cuts open her husband's bank book. In the third act, one character states that \"we are all in the gutter, but some of us are looking at the stars.\" A woman returns an unopened (*) letter from the title character to her husband and claims to have accidentally misplaced the title object at Lord Darlington's place. For ten points, name this play about the title lady suspicious of her husband's affairs with Mrs. Erlynne written by Oscar Wilde.", "answer": "Lady Windermere's Fan", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Lady Windermere's Fan</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Lady Windermere's Fan"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author wrote a short story, dedicated \"In memoriam Ch. P.\", in which Brunofollows the heroin-addicted jazz saxophonist Johnny Carter. In another story by thiswriter, the narrator goes to the Jardin des Plantes to observe the title salamandersbefore turning into one himself. This author of (+) The Pursuer and Axolotl wrote ofa man imagining himself in a motorcycle accident before being being put to death in the War of the Blossoms at the hands of the Motecas, an (*) Aztec tribe. This man also wrote of Letitia and Holanda playing Statues and Attitudes by the train tracks, and in another work, of a photographer tortured by a picture he took that prevented the seduction of an adolescent boy. For ten points, name this author of The Night Face Up, The End of the Game, and Blow Up, an Argentine.", "answer": "Julio Cortazar", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Julio <b><u>Cortazar</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Julio Cortazar"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author wrote a novel in which the title character is a diminutive exchangestudent who stopped a school shooting by killing Trevor Stonefield. He also wrote ofmodel Shannon McFarland secretly feeding female hormones to Brandy Alexanderafter getting her jawbone shot off. This author of (+) Pygmy and Invisible Monsterswrote a story in which a boy loses most of his large intestine in a masturbation accident entitled (*) Guts. He wrote about a character who lives in a house on Paper Street with Marla Singer, who fraudulently frequents support groups, and renders animal fat to produce soap. For ten points, name this author who wrote of the narrator's adventures with Tyler Durden in Fight Club.", "answer": "Chuck Palahniuk                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Chuck <b><u>Palahniuk</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Chuck Palahniuk"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This writer learned to understand Cezanne when he was hungry, and he learnedthe term \"inaccroachable\" from a woman who explained that he could buy clothesor paintings. After winning a pair of horse bets, this man took his wife to eat atMichaud's, where James Joyce ate. This man's wife lost a case with all his original(+) stories at the Gare de Lyon station. This man went on a driving trip with the hypochondriac F. Scott (*) Fitzgerald, taught Ezra Pound to box, and visited Gertrude Stein at her apartment in the Rue de Fleurus. In his autobiography, he was called Tatie by his wife Hadley and told of his cat F. Puss babysitting his infant son Bumby. For ten points, name this American author whose memoir A Moveable Feast describes his time in Paris, when he wrote Big Two-Hearted River and The Sun Also Rises.", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ernest Hemingway</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ernest Hemingway"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "By one account, this character was \"raimented in snowy white\" with a \"pearlgarland\" wound about her head, but a later account omits these descriptions. Thischaracter's home is on an island where \"Four gray walls, and four gray towers,overlook a space of (+) flowers\". This character is roused by hearing the song \"tirralirra, tirra lirra\" in a work told in AAAABCCCB rhyme scheme. This woman is only known to the reaper and only by her (*) singing voice. Her demise is preceded by a mirror cracking \"side to side\", and her body is found in a boat beneath a sign saying \"The web was woven curiously, The charm is broken utterly\". She dies floating downriver after stealing a glance at a passing Lancelot. For ten points, name this woman cursed to weave near Camelot in two poems by Lord Tennyson.", "answer": "the Lady of Shalott", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the Lady of Shalott</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the Lady of Shalott"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The narrator of this work feels that her maid is lying when she claimed to find\"yellow smooches\" on the laundry. The protagonist of this story wakes up in themiddle of the night and argues with her husband about whether her appetite hasimproved. After a week of (+) fog and rain, the narrator claims that her house smellsso bad that she considers burning it down. The narrator tries to see a woman (*)creeping outside through all windows at once. Having been discouraged from writing, the narrator does it in secret and hides from the maid, Jennie. The narrator's husband threatens to send her to Weir Mitchell for treatment, and as a physician, he does not believe that she is sick. For ten points, name this short story about a woman who becomes obsessed with the titular decoration written by Charlotte Perkins Gilman.", "answer": "The Yellow Wallpaper                                                                                                                                                                                                             ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Yellow Wallpaper</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Yellow Wallpaper"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this novel saves the life of Marjorie Stubbs after answering a stranger's telephone. Another character in this novel is told to board an express trainby a man who introduces himself saying \"Zeno of Elea\". In a chapter titled (+) On the carpet of leaves illuminated by the moon, the narrator is sexually overpowered by Madame Miyagi while fantasizing about her daughter, Mikako. The protagonist of this novel is upset when he discovers that his book was actually written by (*) Tazio Bazakbal and that only sixteen pages were included in a printing error. As a result, he consults with Professor Uzzi-Tuzzi, an expert of Cimmerian literature, at the suggestion of the Other Reader. For ten points, identify this novel in which You and Ludmilla attempt to read the titular novel, a work by Italo Calvino.", "answer": "If on a Winter's Night a Traveler (or Se una notte d'inverno un viaggiatore)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>If on a Winter's Night a Traveler</u></b>", "acceptable": ["If on a Winter's Night a Traveler"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Se una notte d'inverno un viaggiatore"}, {"question": "Anne Sexton compared this object to ants \"if their little legs were only/ stitchedon and their heads pasted\". Charles Bukowski discussed this object's prevalenceduring the depression era in a poem called We Ain't Got No Money, Honey, But WeGot [this object]. (+) Joyce Kilmer praised the title Trees for \"intimately liv[ing] with\"this object. The poem somewhere I have never travelled,gladly beyond mentioned this entity's small features, and this word concludes (*) E. E. Cummings's other poem anyone lived in a pretty how town, proceeding \"sun moon stars\". William Carlos Williams's Red Wheel Barrow was glazed with this substance. For ten points, name this substance which drops on the apple trees in Emily Dickinson's Summer Shower.", "answer": "rain", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>rain</u></b>", "acceptable": ["rain"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "While burying his son, Dana Gioia appropriates a Sicilian tradition of plantingan olive or fig tree for this event in his poem Planting a Sequoia. In one poem, peopleare unable to perform this action because they had been tamped \"Where the yewtrees blow like hydras\", and those people \"Unloosed their moons, (+) month aftermonth, to no purpose\". Sylvia Plath laments perfection because it cannot perform this action in the first line of The Munich Mannequins. Philip Larkin ends (*) This Be The Verse advising the reader not to perform this action, after suggesting \"Get out as early as you can\". In The Author to Her Book, Anne Bradstreet likens writing to this action performed by her \"feeble brain\", resulting in its \"ill-formed offspring\". For ten points, name this action in which people become \"mum and dad\".", "answer": "having children (accept equivalents, accept equivalents of birth of a firstborn son)                                                                                                                                                                                                                       ", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>having children</u></b>", "acceptable": ["having children"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept equivalents, accept equivalents of birth of a firstborn son"}, {"question": "At the end of this play, the silhouettes of four characters in a green light brieflyappear on a screen. One character in this play explains another being called a widowdespite having a husband, saying \"In this fact her drama lies\". The stage directionssuggest that four characters wear masks representing (+) remorse, revenge, contempt,and tearful sorrow. A girl is distressed that a man did not recognize her black dress of mourning before he asks her to undress. One woman enters once hats and coats are hung on pegs and is called (*) Madame Pace. A mute boy is found with a revolver and a little girl drowns in a fountain. The Father argues with the Producer about whose reality is more real. For ten points, identify this play in which a family obtrusively stages its own life written by Luigi Pirandello.", "answer": "Six Characters in Search of an Author or (Sei personaggi in cerca d'autore)", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Six Characters in Search of an Author or</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Six Characters in Search of an Author or"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "Sei personaggi in cerca d'autore"}, {"question": "One character in this story does not want a job as a clerk or bartender butclaims that he is \"not particular\". The narrator of this story moves his office closer toCity Hall citing the unwholesomeness of the air. (+) One character suggests that thenarrator walk around the block two or three times after refusing to open the office door. Rumors that that character had worked in a (*) Dead Letter Office in Washington are reported after he dies at the Tombs. That character is given six days notice and a twenty dollar severance package after declining to examine testimony with Turkey, Nippers, and Ginger Nut. For ten points, name this short story whose title character is a law office copyist who \"would prefer not to\" written by Herman Melville.", "answer": "Bartleby, The Scrivener: A Story of Wall Street                                                                                                                                                    ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Bartleby, The Scrivener: A Story of Wall Street</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Bartleby, The Scrivener: A Story of Wall Street"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}